# Dennis Thisner

778-223-4450 dthisner@pm.me github.com/dthisner

I come with over 8+ years of QA (7 of those with automation). I am eager to learn and I adapt easily to new systems and people. My skills include setting up automation testing from scratch, managing my own team, writing robust and easy to keep up to date automation tests, write easy to understand test cases and test plans. Write up tutorial and documentation to make it easier for next person to learn. I bring positive energy and the attitude that nothing is impossible and there is a solution.

#### Skills

- JavaScript, Cypress, Golang, Python
- Frontend & Backend experience
- Github Actions, Circle CI, Jenkins
- AWS, GKE, Azure, Kubernetes, Docker
- Postman, Jmeter, API testing, Cucumber
- Jira, Github for bug tracking
- GraphQL and REST APIs
- Mac OS, Windows, Ubuntu

## **Experience**

**AUGUST 2021 - CURRENT** 

#### Engineering Manager / Plotly, Vancouver

- Mentoring and coaching team members to improve technical skills and leadership abilities.
- Lead the team to successfully delivering Dash Enterprise 5.0, 5.1, 5.2.
- Reduced the supported configurations from 21 to 14, saving about \$140 000 in cost.

JUNE 2021 - AUGUST 2021

## Senior QA Engineer / Plotly, Vancouver

- Created a tool that reduced the seeding env time with over 40%.
- Created the testing process, defining what quality is and teaching it to the rest of the team.
- Setup Cypress successfully and running automatically in the CI and sends out reports into Slack.

MAY 2020 - JUNE 2021

## Senior QA Engineer / Apply Digital, Vancouver

- Successfully educated 4 manual testers to be promoted to QA Engineers.
- Adding native and web mobile E2E tests for iPhone and Android
- Lead QA effort for mobile game which received 2 awards. (Muse and NYX awards 2020)

JAN 2019 - MAY 2020

## **QA Engineer /** Apply Digital, Vancouver

- Introducing and setting up Cypress and easy to follow "Get going with Cypress" tutorials
- Creating a streamline and automated E2E setup and reducing the setup time with over 20%.
- Providing mentorship to junior project manager and product owners.

May 2016 – December 2018

### **QA Engineer /** Cumul8, Vancouver

- Introducing and setting up Cypress and having it running it in the CI.
- Schedule releases and managing the offshore team.
- Rebuilt the whole front-end CI builder, running 15% faster and easier to maintain.

#### **QA Specialist /** Cumul8, Vancouver

- Created the QA testing process with test plans, test strategies for both mobile and web.
- Scheduled releases and setup Testing, Staging and Prod env.
- Pushed to get accurate and simulated customer data for the Prod env.

MARCH 2015 - Nov 2015

#### **QA Dev Support** / United Front Games, Vancouver

- In charge of testing and deploying patches with a team of 8 testers.
- Figured out a way to reproduce issues using a dev environment that was pointing to the prod.
- Created documentation and tutorials to get new hires up to speed.

JAN 2015 - FEB 2015

#### Quality Assurance / Cumul8, Vancouver

- Implemented testing foundation with test plans and test strategies.
- Tested web and mobile applications.
- Thought rest of the team about the testing process.

JAN 2014 - Nov 2014

#### Project Manager / Victory Square Games, Vancouver

- Planned and managed a team of 8 to successfully deliver 4 games to the Microsoft game store
- Successfully helped writing 2 proposal to get government funding
- Reported risks and progress to CEO, angel investors and Microsoft.

#### **Education**

JANUARY 2013 - DECEMBER 2013

## Entertainment Business Management / VFS, Vancouver

An intensive course where I was taught about how the business side works within the entertainment industry, everything from being a great leader, a producer, event manager, and a project manager. Worked on several projects to learn hands on experience with being a manager.

## **Courses / Certifications**

- Testing Javascript May 2022
- Udemy React with Redux March 2021
- Udemy React JS and Redux Aug 2020
- Udemy Selenium WebDriver Jan 2019
- Udemy Web Dev bootcamp April 2018
- Udemy Learn How To Code: Golang Feb 2017
- Udemy Robot Framework Level2 July 2017
- Udemy Robot Framework Level1 May 2017

## **Interests and hobbies**

Skiing, renovation, gardening, board games, Geocaching, archery, painting, carving & playing guitar.

## References available upon request